<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flavio Silva</title>
    <description>Flavio Silva. Solutions Architect at ATD. Passionate about product design.</description>
    <link>https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 00:15:16 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2014 00:15:16 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tweetsheet</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tweetsheet was a few hours weekend project. I wanted an easy way to record
in and out times (for my timesheet).
I thought about using geofencing and iBeacon (to honestly play with iBeacon more than
  doing a timesheet app) but settled with designing a Mac OSX toolbar app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve written an &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@flaviotsf/tweetsheet-a-twitter-based-timesheet-dd45091db6b2&quot;&gt;article on Medium outlining Tweetsheet&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yes, I&amp;#39;m still thinking of some cool usages for iBeacon :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2014/01/03/Tweetsheet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2014/01/03/Tweetsheet/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Parature Outlook Add-in</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We had an awesome workshop on applying David Allen&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://gettingthingsdone.com&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Getting Things Done&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
to our daily routines at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GTD realies heavily on Outlook: folders, tasks, etc. The issue I had was that
we use a ticketing system at work so my Outlook Tasks were not giving me a unified
view of what&amp;#39;s on my plate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I thought... Why not get those tickets inside outlook? To do that I created
a simple Outlook Add-in that shows openend ticket items as well as their details.
Parature&amp;#39;s API&amp;#39;s were not as well documented nor fully featured but I managed to
get the bulk of it done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a huge time-saver and made sure the team didn&amp;#39;t drop the ball on any
opened item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/gtd-parature.png&quot; alt=&quot;Outlook AddIn&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Many folks use the add-in on a daily basis!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One change I made since its creation was to start tracking projects and other
larger enhancements in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trello.com&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;.
Having a board display is a great communication
tool between team members and upper management. We&amp;#39;re following a basic KANBAN
flow - using Trello - and it has been working great for us!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2014/01/02/Parature-Outlook/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2014/01/02/Parature-Outlook/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Twitter Backstage</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The idea behind Twitter backstage was to create an aggregated page
of tweets and information about a certain hashtag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perfect fits are transitional events like conferences
or sporting events like Winbledon or the US Open, for exemple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backstage used a &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodejs.org&quot;&gt;node.js&lt;/a&gt; module to connect to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dev.twitter.com/docs/api/streaming&quot;&gt;Twitter Streaming API&lt;/a&gt;.
Every time a certain tweet matched my watched hashtag, Backstage woud:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save the data into a no-sql (MongoDB) database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run a few other processes. I was extracting links as well so I could
build a &amp;#39;top list&amp;#39; of links shared. To do that, I used Cheerio to extract titles, descriptions and thumbnail images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of Backstage was to have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of most popular tweets on that topic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of media items associated with that hashtag (videos, images)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Curated list by the organizer of the hashtag of who to follow (and tweets about those folks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A branded landing page that pushed the hashtag even further.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still think the idea is great but haven&amp;#39;t had time to push it further
into development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2014/01/01/Backstage/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2014/01/01/Backstage/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ATD Education Site Redesign</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Together with the ATD team and a vendor we redesigned the Education section
of our site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal was to make it easy for folks to find the best program for them
and to make registration easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do that, we made sure our landing page had many entry points for our
facetted search page. We also ensured to have many filter options
for our users varying from topic, location, price among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also spent a good amount of time on our program detail pages, making sure they
are not overly long and but still contain all the information necessary
for someone to be able to tell if a certain program is right for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also worked on lots of other pages and functionality including our Learning Roadmap,
Facilitator search pages and all. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.astd.org/Education&quot;&gt;ATD Education&lt;/a&gt; site!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/edu-search.png&quot; alt=&quot;Education Search&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The education search page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/edu-easy-cart.png&quot; alt=&quot;Education Easy Add to Cart&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Adding a program to your cart is easy!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/edu-fac-search.png&quot; alt=&quot;Facilitator Search&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Among other things, we allow to search for facilitators.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/edu-detail.png&quot; alt=&quot;Detail Page&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Our program detail page. We used &lt;a href=&quot;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/staticmaps/&quot;&gt;static Google Maps images&lt;/a&gt; to show the location while
not taxing performance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2013/01/01/Education-Redesign/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2013/01/01/Education-Redesign/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Make a Point</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Make a Point was a very cool system to work on. It started with a simple idea:
can we create a form for people to &amp;#39;praise&amp;#39; their coworkers? Then we may let
them exchange praises by gift cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought the idea was great, but a form by itself would not create a level
of engagement that we were looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I thought: Why not create a simple system that folks can see who is receiving
praise and all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how Make a Point looks today:
&lt;img src=&quot;/public/map-landing.png&quot; alt=&quot;Make a Point Landing Page&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#39;ve also made the site resposive and added some special tags so it can be
added to iPhones and Androids as a webapp. This way you can send points anytime!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I built an admin section for our HR department so they can track and
manage employees and run reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/map-claim.png&quot; alt=&quot;Make a Point Claim&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Make a Point claim page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/map-detail.png&quot; alt=&quot;Make a Point Detail Page&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Make a Point detail page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/map-admin.png&quot; alt=&quot;Make a Point Admin&quot;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Make a Point admin page&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2012/01/03/Make-a-Point/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2012/01/03/Make-a-Point/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ATD Lead Scoring Algorithm</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We decided to create a lead scoring algorithm to be able to deliver relevant
content to our customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me and some other ATD folks sat on a room and decided that - at a minimum -
we should be able to attribute lead score points to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Orders&lt;/strong&gt;: each of our products are mapped to our areas of interest. We should
be able to use that information to know what a customer is interested in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web site visits&lt;/strong&gt;: we published a ton of blogs, articles and newsletters. Those
are also some great data points.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emails&lt;/strong&gt;: emails are still a big part of how we communicate
with our members. We need to take in consideration the items they click on
to understand what are their interests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To have that information we had to put a lot of things in place, between
tagging content effectively, used web analytics to all it&amp;#39;s pontential and creating
systems that would allow us to track things such as email link clicks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We waited a few weeks for this data to start to populate and created a function
that assings a point for each of those activities. We also added a decay factor
to each of them so a &amp;quot;Web Article Point&amp;quot; today is worth &amp;quot;1&amp;quot; but a year ago it will
be worth 0.02, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also decided to &amp;#39;flatten&amp;#39; the point structure a bit (having 50, 100, 1000) points
might be the same when &amp;#39;interest&amp;#39; is concerned. So we wanted to stay with a 0-100 range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At ATD we have over 10 lead score fields. One for each of our content areas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use this information to target ads on our site, recommended products and a lot
of other things!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2012/01/02/Lead-Scoring/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2012/01/02/Lead-Scoring/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ATD Redirect System</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The ATD Redirect System was born soon after we started discussing what we
could do to have an effective lead scoring algorithm at ATD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have a pretty sophisticated web analytics implementation but we wanted to
ensure we had an effective way to track incoming links from emails. If we are
promoting an external site that is outside our web properties we can still track
tagging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emails are a primary form of communication between ATD and its members
so we devised a system where one could create links and tag them by various
tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each time a customer clicks a redirect link, we make sure to log that into
a SQL Database where we can later report on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another very cool result of the redirect system is being able to fix a link
after an email was sent. Since the redirect is stable (we use a Redirect ID)
the target link can be easily fixed without much impact since we opted to use
a 302 redirect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/redirect-system.png&quot; alt=&quot;Redirect System&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from Redirects we can append tons of other information to redirects
including discount, affiliate, and various other codes used for tracking
inbound marketing in tools like Google Analytics and Coremetrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Redirect System still is a huge success. We have over 10,000 redirect
links created and tons and tons of logs (almost 3,000,000 records)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2012/01/01/Redirect-System/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2012/01/01/Redirect-System/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ATD Conference Predictive Dashboard</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At ATD I&amp;#39;ve always seen folks run around gathering reports for our
annual conference. Observing that, I thought it would be a great idea
to create a simple dashboard that not only contained the data up to now
but also would have an estimate of how many more conferences we would sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This little dashboard was a huge success and is still used today. Of course
some improvements were made to the projection algorythm since then, taking
in consideration more factors like early bird rates and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example (numbers were blurred since they are proprietary information).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/predictive-nocomments.png&quot; alt=&quot;Conference Predictive Dashboard&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the widespread of visualization tools like Tableau it will make sense
to move and improve on the predictive logic of this dashboard
to a specialized tool which will allow for a far greater analysis
like tracking goals based on certain customer segmentation criteria, for example.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2011 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2011/01/01/ICE-Predictive-Dashboard/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2011/01/01/ICE-Predictive-Dashboard/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>iXLink Pricelist Exchange</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;iXLink was created to facilitate the exchange of price lists between telecom
providers. I had a great time working with an amazing team of people in the
early days of the iXLink tool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may know, Verizon - for example - does not own all the cables and network
between your home and your friend in London. When you place a call, Verizon
needs to identify how it will route your call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies to do using a variety of factors (price, quality, etc.). One of the
biggest challenges in the industry was that - to my surprise at the time - they
used mostly Microsoft Excel spreadsheets to exchange pricing information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, imagine hundreds of companies exchanging excel files and - as you can imagine -
each of them had a different format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iXLink set to create a standard for companies to exchange price lists. An internal
format was created but pushing a whole industry to move from Excel to an agreed
XML format is challenging. To soften this transition we build a sophisticated system
to define commonalities between price lists and effectively convert them from their
input Excel files into our XML file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, we build interfaces to allow companies to select their business partners
and also integration with Telarix&amp;#39;s iXTools system - that manages prices, routing and
reporting on some of the largest telecom companies in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2007 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2007/01/01/iXLink/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2007/01/01/iXLink/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Realtime Sales</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Realtime Sales was a project I worked on waaay back in 2006. I had the idea
of adding real-time information from some of Mercatto&amp;#39;s retail stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This system was a huge success. It completly changed the way management would
act on information. Before it, they had to rely on phone calls or simply waiting
the next day to have sales information and act on it (reduce / increase prices,
decide what inventory to send to the store, etc.). With real-time sales they
could track the performance of the store, salespeople and product lines and act
on that information &lt;em&gt;fast&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/public/vtr.png&quot; alt=&quot;Realtime Sales&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, not all stores had broadband connection in them. A few days after
Realtime Sales was implemented on the first store broadband was added to all
stores! It&amp;#39;s cool to see a system created back in 2006 with some of the same
elements we might find today in dashboard including gauges, charts and an easy
representation of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Yes, that is SQL Server 2000 Query Analyzer and Internet Explorer. The good
old times.... haha&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2006 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2006/01/01/Realtime-Sales/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://twitter.com/flaviotsf//2006/01/01/Realtime-Sales/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
